



# Kathleen Haggard

Attorney

Kathleen Haggard advises cities, school districts, port districts, and other municipalities on a broad range of legal issues, including public works and construction, land use, employment law, and public records. She has extensive litigation and appellate court experience in public works, public records, and land use cases. Kathleen conducts workplace investigations on a range of issues including discrimination, harassment, sexual misconduct, and whistleblower claims.

## **CONTACT**

Tel (206) 622-0203 Fax (206) 223-2003 kathleen@pfrwa.com

## PROFESSIONAL POSITIONS

Attorney, Porter Foster Rorick, 2004-present

Assistant City Attorney, Torts Division, City of Seattle, 2001-2004

Assistant Attorney General, Social and Health Services Division, 1999-2001

## **EDUCATION**

University of Washington School of Law, Seattle, Washington, J.D., 1999 Managing Editor, Washington Law Review

University of Washington, Seattle, Washington, B.A., cum laude, 1996

## PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Washington State Association of Municipal Attorneys

## AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Municipal law
- Public works
- Land use and code enforcement

- Workplace investigations
- Civil litigation
- Public records

#### PRACTICE HIGHLIGHTS

- City of Tacoma v. City of Bonney Lake, et al., 173 Wn.2d 584 (2012). Secured unanimous victory from the Washington Supreme Court on behalf of City of Federal Way in a water system finance case.
- Thun v. City of Bonney Lake, 164 Wn. App. 755 (2011). Persuaded the Court of Appeals to sustain the summary judgment dismissal of plaintiff's inverse condemnation claim.
- Federal Way Sch. Dist. No. 210 v. State, 167 Wn.2d 514 (2009). Worked with team of attorneys to sue the State of Washington over inequitable school funding.
- City of Bonney Lake v. Milestone Homes, 145 Wn. App. 118 (2008). Persuaded the Court of Appeals to sustain city's decision to deny subdivision approval.
- *Port of Shelton v. City of Shelton.* Defeated Growth Management Act challenge to area-wide rezone within airport influence area.
- Successfully defended Washington cities and public ports in multiple public records lawsuits concerning issues as diverse as national security and terrorism prevention, First Amendment rights, third party injunctions, and PRA best practices.
- Obtained full recovery on an \$800,000 construction defect claim against the supplier and contractor of a sewer membrane bio-reactor facility.
- Conducted dozens of workplace investigations concerning employee misconduct, whistleblower complaints and agency/constituent interactions.
- Defeated attempt to place an illegal initiative on a city's ballot.

#### SELECTED PRESENTATIONS

- "We're Gonna Need a Bigger Boat: A Deep Dive into the Scope of the PRA and its Exemptions," WCIA Spring Conference, May 2018.
- "School Siting Smackdown: Bridging the Urban/Rural Divide under the Growth Management Act," Council of School Attorneys Annual Meeting, April 2018.
- "Information In, Information Out: Troubleshooting in the PRA Techverse," WCIA Spring Conference, April 2017.
- "Disaster Preparedness Workshop: PRA Edition," WCIA Fall Conference, October 2016.
- "Ripped from the Headlines: Public Records in the Modern World," Association of Washington Cities Annual Conference, June 2015.
- "Three Car Pile-up: Collision of the FMLA, ADA, and Workers' Compensation," Public Agency Risk Managers Association, September 2014.
- "Picketing, Protesting, and Advertising: The (un)Holy Trinity of Public Space Regulation," WSBA CLE on *Zoning, Current Issues and Future Challenges*, March 2013.
- "Trash, Traffic, and Traditional Public Forums: Regulating Signage amidst the Rise of Commercial Speech," Hearing Examiners Association of Washington, October 2012.